## Kristin De Salme

Phone: (210) 445-2192 | Email: kristin.desalme@gmail.com | San Antonio, TX

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristin-desalme/ Portfolio: https://kr1istin.github.io/portfolio react/

GitHub: https://github.com/KR1ISTIN

As a FullStack and Dental Hygienist, I bring excellent communication and teamwork skills, along with a strong eagerness and willingness to learn. While transitioning from oral healthcare to programming may seem unexpected, I thrive on challenges, and web development provides the perfect canvas for my skills. I look forward to contributing my diverse experiences and enthusiasm to a new team and making a meaningful impact in the field.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, SQL, HTML5, BASH
- Frameworks/Libraries: Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Node.js, Express.js, React, Handlebars, Bootstrap, MaterialUI, Bulma, Tailwind
- Databases: MySQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Sequelize, Mongoose
- Tools/Technologies: RESTful APIs, Maven, Docker, Microservices, JWT, Auth0, OAuth2, Bycrpt, GraphQL, Jest, Object-oriented programming, Heroku, Git, IntelliJ, pgAdmin4, MySQL Workbench, MVC Pattern, GithubActions CI/CD Pipeline
- **Project Management:** Team Collaboration, Communication, Agile Development, Scrum, Sprint, Kanban, Jira, Github Projects, Wireframming
- AWS: IAM, ECS, Elastic Beanstalk, AWS RDS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Backend Developer ARP Roofing and Remodeling

2024-Present Remote

Contracted to create an app that is a central source for customer related data.

#### **Key Accomplishments/In Progress:**

- Reduced latency in lead creation by enabling sales reps to quickly input leads on the go.
- *Effectively* created and managed a database to ensure proper organization, security, and accessibility of information.
- Reduced operational debt by integrating multiple APIs to streamline data exchange and enhance system functionality.
- Implementation unit tests using Jest to ensure code quality and reliability.

Volunteering to help a childhood cancer nonprofit. Built a key-single page featuring update operations, database consultation and implementation, and mentoring in Git versioning control, and maintenance in code base.

## **Key Accomplishments:**

- Collaborated with team to refine database architecture, ensuring efficiency
- Successfully trained a partner in Git versioning control, fostering collaborative and efficient development environments
- Successfully implemented RESTful APIs using Django and Python for user operations
- Enhancing cleanliness in code base by addressing errors, with unit tests

## Dental Hygienist TruSmile Dentistry

2017-Present

2023-Present

Remote

San Antonio, TX

Perform dental cleanings and educate patients on how to maintain excellent oral hygiene.

### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Established a strong rapport with through active listening, empathetic communication, and personalized care, enhancing patient cooperation and dental experience.
- Collaborated with dental colleagues, sharing insights and assisting in complex cases, fostering a cohesive team environment that improved patient care and satisfaction.
- Led training for colleagues, imparting essential skills and knowledge to elevate the team's expertise and improve workflow efficiency.
- Promoted to Lead Hygienist after one year, recognizing leadership and exceptional performance

#### **PROJECTS**

#### MealMappr

## Github Repo Link

#### **Deployed Link to MealMappr**

MealMappr, a team project, that allows access for users to manage their personalized meal plans

#### **Role: FullStack and Project Management**

Implemented Models, Routes for CRUD both front and backend, Login/Logout functionality, Scrum Master, UI design for modals

**Tools/Technologies:** Heroku, HTML, JavaScript, Node, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars, TailWind, Full Calendar, Bycrpt, Team Collaboration, Agile Development, KanBan, Scrum, Paired Programming, Git, Github Projects, Wireframe

#### YardGems

## **Github Repo Link**

## **Deployed Link to YardGems**

YardGems, a team project, utilizing the MERN Stack. Allowing users to search and post garage sales

## **Role: FullStack and Project Management**

Implemented React Google Maps API, Models, GraphQL, Routes for CRUD both front and backend, secure Login/Logout functionality, partial implementation UI design, Scrum Master

Tools/Technologies: React, React Router DOM, Heroku, Mongoose, JavaScript, React Google Maps API, GraphQL, MaterialUI, Express.js, Node.js, Apollo Server, JWT, Bycrpt, HTML, CSS, Team Collaboration, Agile Development, Kanban, Scrum, Paired Programming, Git, Github Projects, Wireframe

#### **EDUCATION**

Udemy Certificate, Master Java, Spring 6 and Spring Boot 3 with JDBC, JPA, May 2024 Security, Docker and Microservices with Telusko

A 42-hour course in mastering Java, Spring, Spring Boot, JPA, AOP, with the addition of Docker and Microservices

## **Bootcamp Certificate, Full Stack Web Development: UTSA**

**July 2023** 

A rigorous 24-week, project driven course, in full stack JavaScript Web Development Certification

## Associate, Dental Hygiene: Concorde Career College

May 2017

A 18-month accelerated program, focusing on oral hygiene and clinical care